Guide to the Japanese-American Relocation Centers records, 1935-1953.
Japanese-American Relocation Centers records,
- Series II. Manzanar
  - Congressional Records
    - Congressional Records: hearings before House Committee on expatriation, on military affairs (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Tolan Committee
    - Tolan Committee: excerpts (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Tolan Committee: testimony (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Dies Committee
    - Dies Committee versus WRA testimony (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - House UnAmerican Activities Commission
    - House UnAmerican Activities Commission: report on Tule Lake riot, report on Tule lake segregation, on WRA (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - House UnAmerican Activities Commission: report on Japanese Activities (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - National Defense Migration
    - National Defense Migration: hearings before the House, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 15-18)
  - WRA National Administration
    - WRA Administrative Instructions (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - WRA Administrative Manual (Box 15, Folder 20-21)
    - WRA Administrative Notices (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - WRA Administrative notice: Handbook release (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - WRA Information Digest, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 24-25)
    - WRA Abstracts (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - WRA Solicitor's opinions (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - WRA quarterly reports, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - WRA documents, misc. (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - wRA general (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - WRA Wartime Exile the Exclusion of the Japanese from the West- California and her less favored minorities (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography on evacuation (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - WRA Community government in war relocation centers (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - WRA impounded people Japanese Americans in the relocation centers (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - WRA the evacuated people, a quantitative description (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - WRA in motion: The Postwar Adjustment of the Evacuated Japanese Americans (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - JACL miscellaneous papers (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Rumor over Hawaii (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
    - Miscellaneous reports, "The Hand of Mr. Haan", "The Yellow Paper", etc. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Community Government
    - Project analyses sections (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Other Camps: Tule Lake (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Project Analysis: Denver, Colorado resettlement study (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Project Analysis: Conversation with relocated Japanese Americans in Denver (Box 16, Folder 14-16)
    - Project Analysis: report on Social Adjustment (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Community Analysis Section
    - WRA General reports, letters, directives, correspondence, bibliography (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Manzanar reports, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 19-25)
    - Manzanar reports, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 26-31)
    - Chronology of Manzanar events (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Project Reports
    - Monthly summary of Manzanar activity, 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Project directors reports, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Information Center Daily Reports
    - Information center daily reports, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 35-37)
    - Information center daily reports, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Town Hall Daily Reports
    - Report of block activities, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 3-6)
  - Block Leaders' Council
    - Reports and minutes (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Block Managers Assembly
    - Block Managers Assembly minutes, 1942-1944 (Box 17, Folder 8-11)
  - Historical Documentation
    - Reports 1-25 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Reports 26-49 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Reports 50-65 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Reports 66-86, miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - History of Internal Government at Manzanar
    - History of internal government at Manzanar (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - General Information
    - General information: pamphlets, reports, events (Box 17, Folder 17-18)
  - Education
    - Pre-school report with photographs (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - High school autobiographies (Box 17, Folder 20-21)
    - Adult education English compositions and curriculum outline (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Medical and Health Survey
    - Reports, documents, observations (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Manzanar Miscellaneous Reports
    - Census report (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Fence report (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Other reports (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Welfare Hearings: Family interviews pertaining to resettlement
    - Welfare hearings: summary statistics and notes (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews A-J (Box 17, Folder 28-29)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews K (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews M (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews N (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews O (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews S (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews T (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews U-W (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Welfare hearings: interviews Y (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Leave Clearance General Cases and Outlines
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: A-E (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: F, H (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: I, K (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: M (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: N-O (Box 18, Folder 16-17)
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: S-T (Box 18, Folder 18-19)
    - Leave clearance general cases and outlines: U, Y (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
    - Leave clearance cases: Edsen M. Kurose (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Leave clearance cases: Mrs. Hide Yamaguchi (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Leave clearance cases: Richard K. Mizukami (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - General information about applications for leave clearance, reports and studies of reference letters for leave clearance (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - General information about leave clearance, individual records, research data for letter study (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Internee's letters of recommendation for leave clearance (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Army and leave clearance: registration and WRA directives (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Relocation
    - WRA Community Analysis Relocation Studies (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Wartime Civil Control administration releases (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Relocation resettlement bulletin (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Relocation study (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - WRA Directives and Manzanar council meetings (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous papers on relocation (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Manuscript on loyalty (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence about relocation (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Opler's personal letters from relocated persons (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Opler's miscellaneous correspondence (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Opler's personal postcards (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Relocation news reprints (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
  - Segregation
    - Studies of segregants without foreign travel (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Data for segregant report (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Tule Lake segregants (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Reports of segregants who changed their answers (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Data on segregants: H-M (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Data on segregants: N-Y (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Roster of segregants (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous reports, data, correspondence on segregation (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Repatriation
    - Report on repatriat-expatriate group at Manzanar (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Report notes (Box 19, Folder 13-14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 50 Miscellaneous scenes from relocation campes. Sketches. (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Anti-Japanese propaganda (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
    - Articles about Japan and Japanese, Bibliography (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Japanese language notes (Box 19, Folder 19-20)
    - Missionary activity in Japan (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Report on Japanese community at Terminal Island (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Report of the Japanese community at Saipan and Tinian, with photo, Manzanar High Yearbook (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Clipping file on Japanese-American relocation
    - Arkansas Democrat (Little Rock) 1945 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Baltimore News and Post 1943-1944 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Baltimore Sun 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - The Boston Daily Globe 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Boston Herald 1945-1946 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Cheyenne Tribune 1945 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Chicago Daily News 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Chicago Daily Tribune 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Chicago Sun 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Christian Advocate (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Christian Century (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Christian Science Monitor 1943 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Christian Science Monitor 1944 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Christian Science Monitor 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Cincinnati Enquirer (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Collier's Magazine (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Des Moines Register 1943 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Des Moines Register 1943 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Fresno Bee 1943-1945 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Hollywood Citizen Newa 1945 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Honolulu Advertiser 1946 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Honolulu Star Bulletin July 1944 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Honolulu Star Bulletin Aug. 1944 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Honolulu Star Bulletin Sept. 1944 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Japanese-American Courier (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Japanese-American Mirror (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Klamath Falls Herald-News (Oregon) (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - L.A. Daily News May-June 1942 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - L.A. Daily News July 1942 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - L.A. Daily News Aug. 1942 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - L.A. Daily News Sept.1942 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - L.A. Daily News Oct.1942 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - L.A. Daily News Nov.-Dec. 1942 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - L.A. Daily News Jan.-Mar. 1943 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - L.A. Daily News Apr.-June 1943 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - L.A. Daily News July-Dec. 1943 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - L.A. Daily News Jan.-Feb. 1944 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - L.A. Daily News Mar.-April 1944 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - L.A. Daily News May 1944 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - L.A. Daily News June-July 1944 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - L.A. Daily News Aug.-Dec. 1944 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - L.A. Daily News 1945 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - L.A. Examiner Jan. 1942-June 1943, See also: Box 22 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Life Magazine (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Milwaukee Journal 1943 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Milwaukee Journal Jan.-June 1944 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Milwaukee Journal July-Dec. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Nation (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - The New Pacific (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - The New Republic (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Newsweek (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The New World (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - New York Times 1941-1942 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - New York Times Jan.-Oct. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - New York Times Nov.-Dec. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - New York Times Jan.-April 1944 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - New York Times May-June 1944 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - New York Times July-Aug. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - New York Times Sept. 1944-1947 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - New York Herald Tribune (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - New York Journal and American (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Oakland Tribune (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Omaha World-Herald (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Pacific Citizen Jan.-Mar. 1942 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Pacific Citizen June 1942-Oct. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Clippings from the Pacific Citizen, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Pasadena Post (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Pasadena Star News Dec. 1943-May 1944 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Pasadena Star News June 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Philadelphia Record Oct. 1943-July 1944 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Philadelphia Record Aug. 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Pittsburgh Post Gazette (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Pittsburgh Press (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - P.M. Daily 1943-Jan. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - P.M. Daily Feb.-June 1944 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - P.M.Daily July 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Portland Oregonian (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Portland Oregon Journal (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Progress Bulletin (Pomona California) (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Rafu Shimpo Dec. 1939-Mar. 1942 (Los Angeles) (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Reno Gazette (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Sacramento Bee (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Sacramento Union (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch Oct. 1943-Apr. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch May-Oct. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Salt Lake Tribune Oct. 1943-Feb. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Salt Lake Tribune Mar. 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - San Francisco Chronicle 1941-1942 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco Chronicle 1943 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Chronicle Jan.-Feb. 1944 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco Chronicle Mar.-May 1944 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - San Francisco Chronicle June-Aug.1944 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - San Francisco Chronicle Sept.1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - San Francisco Examiner (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - San Francisco News (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Saturday Evening Post (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Seattle Post Intelligencer (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Spokane Spokesman Review (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Stockton Record (Calif.) (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Time Magazine (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Washington News (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Washington Post 1943-Oct. 1945 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Washington Post Nov.-Dec. 1945 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Washington Post 1946 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Washington Star (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Washington Times-Herald (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - L.A. Examiner 1943 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - L.A. Examiner Jan.-Feb. 1944 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - L.A. Examiner Mar.-June 1944 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - L.A. Examiner July-Sept. 1944 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - L.A. Examiner Oct. 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - L.A. Herald Express (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - L.A. Herald Express (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - L.A. Sentinel (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - L.A. Times 1940-July 1942 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - L.A. Times Aug. 1942-Mar. 1943 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - L.A. Times Apr.-Dec. 1943 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - L.A. Times Jan.-Mar. 1944 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - L.A. Times Apr.-June 1944 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - L.A. Times July-Aug. 1944 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - L.A. Times Sept.-Oct. 1944 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - L.A. Times Dec. 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous A-B (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous C-D (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous E-L (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous M-R (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous S (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous T-Z (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Crossroads -The All English Japanese American Newspaper Nov.-Dec. 1948 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Crossroads Jan.-Mar. 1949 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Crossroads Apr.-June 1949 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Crossroads July-Sept. 1949 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Crossroads Oct.-Dec. 1949 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Crossroads Jan.-Mar. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Crossroads Apr.-June 1950 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Crossroads July-Sept. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Crossroads Oct.-Dec. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Crossroads Jan.-Mar. 1951 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Crossroads Apr.-June 1951 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Crossroads July-Sept. 1951 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Crossroads Oct.-Dec. 1951 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Crossroads Jan.-Mar. 1952 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Crossroads Apr.-June 1952 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Crossroads July-Sept. 1952 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Crossroads Oct.-Dec. 1952 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Crossroads Jan.-Feb. 1953 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Crossroads Apr.-June 1953 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Crossroads July-Aug. 1953 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Series III. Oversized material
  - Miscellaneous
    - Outside Employment Bulletins May-July 1943 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Outside Employment Bulletins Aug.-Oct. 1943 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers- Nov. 1942-Mar. 1943 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - State Department publications, press bulletins (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Minutes JACL Special Emergency National Conference, Nov. 17-24, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Supplement to Minutes, JACL Special Emergency National Conference, Nov. 17-42, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - JACL Anti-Discrimination Committee (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Manzanar high school newspaper, Campus Pepper, ten issues, May 1943 - June 1944 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Watercolors
    - Photos of watercolors (Box 25, Folder 8)
      CD-1642
    - Slides of watercolors (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Small boxes of slides of watercolors (1-40) (Box 25)
    - Small boxes of slides of watercolors (41-98) (Box 25)
    - Small boxes of slides of watercolors (81-120) (Box 25)
    - Small boxes of slides of watercolors (121-137) (Box 25)
    - #1 - #5 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - #6 - #10 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - #11 - #15 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - #16 - #20 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - #21 - #25 (Box 26a, Folder 5)
    - #26 -#30 (Box 26a, Folder 6)
    - #31 - #35 (Box 26a, Folder 7)
    - #36 - #40 (Box 26a, Folder 8)
    - #41 - #45 (Box 26a, Folder 9)
    - #46 - #50 (Box 26a, Folder 10)
    - #51 - #55 (Box 26a, Folder 11)
    - #56 - #60 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - #61 - #65 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - #66 - #70 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - #71 - #75 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - #76 - #80 (Box 27a, Folder 5)
    - #81 - #85 (Box 27a, Folder 6)
    - #86 - #90 (Box 27a, Folder 7)
    - #91 - #95 (Box 27a, Folder 8)
    - #96 - #100 (Box 27a, Folder 9)
    - #101 - #105 (Box 27a, Folder 10)
    - #106 - #110 (Box 27a, Folder 11)
    - #111 - #115 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - #116 - #120 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - #121 - #127 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - #128 - #133 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - #134 - #137 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Red Cross Scrapbook "Out of the Desert" (Box 28)
    - Boundary Map of Manzanar Relocation Area in California (Mapcase-folder 2)
    - Organization Chart of Poston, Arizona (Mapcase-folder 2)
    - Blueprint of Manzanar (Mapcase-folder 2)
    - Colorado River Indian Irrigation Project plot plan (Mapcase-folder 1)
    - Evacuee interview notes and personality study notes arranged alphabetically by last name on paper slips, and staff meeting notes arranged chronologically on paper slips (Box 31-37)
    - The Album, 442nd Combat Team 1943, and Our World, Manzanar California - 1943-1944, Manzanar High (Box 19)